#### KARTHIKEYAN KR

New Perungalathur, Email: grinkarthi@gmail.com

Pin - 600063, **Mobile : +91-7418672382** 

Chennai. Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/grinkarthi

### **SUMMARY:**

A senior software engineer with 3.5 years of industrial experience in Designing, Development, Deployment and Maintenance of new back-end software applications, libraries and frameworks for Mobius. Experience building both small scripts and large systems in Python. Interact with various teams across Mobius as part of the development process. Ability to learn quickly and solve complex problems under minimal supervision.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

**Designation:** Senior Software Engineer

Organization Name: Mobius Knowledge Services, Chennai

**Duration:** Nov 2016 - till date **Duties and Responsibilities:** 

- Analyzing new technologies and tools required for the organization.
- Follow Agile development culture and open to perform multiple roles as demanded by the project.
- Convert the business requirements into specifications for applications and develop programming codes for the applications.

**Designation:** Software Engineer

Organization Name: Mobius Knowledge Services, Chennai

**Duration:** May 2016 - Nov2016 **Duties and Responsibilities:** 

- Develop codes for program and get them reviewed from the seniors.
- Remove the minor program bugs and perform other troubleshooting functions.
- Participate in meetings with the seniors to learn about the project specifications and client's expectations for the software.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

• Languages : Python, Core Java

DBMS Packages : PostgresSQL, SQL Server, MongoDB
Development Tools : PyDev, Eclipse, VS Code, SVN

• Operating Systems : Ubuntu, Windows10

• Web Services : HTML, Javascript, JSON, RESTful

• Python Frameworks : Flask, Pandas, Jinja2, Stomp, Boto3, pika,

SqlAlchemy, Requests, unittest

• Services : AWS, Apache ActiveMQ

ElasticSearch, RabbitMQ

• Web Server : Apache 2, Apache Tomcat

## **EDUCATION QUALIFICATION:**

- B.TECH in Information Technology (2012-2016) from Ponjesly College of Engineering, Nagercoil with 7.47% CGPA.
- HSC from Hindu Vidyalaya, Marthandam with 79.1% aggregate.
- SSLC from Hindu Vidyalaya, Marthandam with 78.6% aggregate.

# **PROJECT PROFILE:**

• ScrapeWorks.

**Description:** A web application used to manage customer's crawl requests. They can either run the existing bot or request for new bot. A web application is developed using **python Flask** and components were developed to run the bots. **RabbitMQ** was used to create communication between web app and components. **ElasticSearch** is used to dump the log files. **PostgresSQL** is used for data management.

**Ref:** https://www.scrape.works

• Data Studio.

**Description:** Data Studio is a data integration and orchestration platform that quickly delivers recent, valid and enriched data for direct consumption by enterprises, empowering them for faster and effective decision making. Web Service for this platform is developed using **Python Flask** framework, while its functional operations were developed using **Java. PostgresSQL** is used for data management.

**Ref:** https://www.mobiusservices.com/products-and-platforms/platforms/data-studio

### **SKILLS AND QUALIFICATIONS:**

- Strong **Python** skills, in addition to development using **agile** techniques, **test-driven** development, and Object Oriented programming concepts.
- Mentor and provide technical leadership to junior members of the team.
- Basic understandings of front end technologies, such as JavaScript, HTML and AJAX.
- A strong understanding of common web development techniques, e.g. **REST, JSON** etc.
- Familiarity with Object Relational Mappers like **SqlAlchemy** and **JOOQ**.
- Have used JIRA / Redmine and other collaboration tools in a team environment.
- Integrated Payment gateway system(PayPal).
- Experience with Amazon Web Services like EC2, Lambda, API Gateway, S3.
- Experience using system tools, **source control** systems like **SVN**.
- Includes unit tests for feature areas to achieve established code coverage targets .
- Experience providing Continuous Integration solutions using tools such as **Jenkins**.
- Proficient in Linux, including scripting and deployment of applications.

Place: Chennai. (KARTHIKEYAN KR)